ENEDA XHAMBAZI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

enedaxhambazi@gmail.com

4 201-956-1998

• Manchester, NH

neda.dev

in eneda

neda8

SUMMARY

I am a highly creative and detail-oriented Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, and Node. With a diverse background in administrative support, I've developed exceptional problem-solving, organizational, and project-management skills. I am currently based in Saddle Brook, NJ, with plans to relocate to Manchester, NH by December 2023.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript (ES6+, Node), TypeScript, Python 3, HTML5, CSS3/Sass

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: Express.js, React.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma

TOOLS: MongoDB, Git, Netlify, Heroku, Vite, Webpack, Cloudinary

PROJECTS

t'day Mar 2021 - Present

Fully responsive social networking site built with JavaScript, Node and Express, using MongoDB for database and data visualization. t'day is an anonymous online journal where users rate their day on a scale of 1-5, post and comment on public entries, and view the aggregate average rating score in real-time, with the ability to filter by age group, country, and gender. Additional features include private user profiles with post and comment history, bookmarks, a comprehensive search page, private, encrypted journals, and both user-specific and collective charts pages displaying ratings data.

tday.co | github.com/eneda8/tday

YelpCamp Apr 2021 - May 2021

Yelp but for campgrounds: a fully responsive CRUD site where users can create/edit/remove their own profiles for campgrounds across the country and review others' campground profiles. YelpCamp features geolocation using Mapbox and user authentication and authorization using Passport.js. Layouts were created using EJS and the Cloudinary API was used for image storage.

secret-fortress-70149.herokuapp.com | github.com/eneda8/yelp-camp

EDUCATION

The College of New Jersey

Aug 2010 - May 2014

B.A. in Psychology, Minor in Creative Writing

Summa Cum Laude (4.0 GPA), Phi Beta Kappa Society, Published in *Political Psychology* (2013), Peter Wood Award in Creative Writing

Florence University of the Arts

Jan 2013 - May 2013

EMPLOYMENT

Career Transition Jan 2020 - Present

Transitioning into a career in web development. Completed 7 online courses/bootcamps on Udemy and Scrimba, totaling over 200 lecture hours. Completed and successfully deployed 9 projects, including 2 feature-rich, production-grade, full-stack web applications.

Ennead Architects - Executive Assistant - New York, NY

Sep 2018 - Jan 2020

Supported 4 Partners of architectural design firm with scheduling, travel arrangements, expense tracking, and staffing changes. Processed international business visa applications. Spearheaded office relocation efforts for staff of 200+ employees. Supported marketing department in updating business cards for all employees using inDesign.

Trust Company of the West - *Administrative Assistant* - Los Angeles, CA

May 2015 - Feb 2016

Coordinated meetings and travel arrangements for 4 Equity Research Analysts, monitored earnings reporting using Factset, and tracked and reported travel expenses using Concur.

Fader & Associates - Executive Assistant - Teaneck, NJ

Jul 2014 - Feb 2015

Successfully managed 5 qualitative market research studies for Fortune 500 clients, from initiation to completion. Developed research methodologies and materials. Made travel arrangements for and attended field research, supervising participants, recruiters, and onsite personnel. Handled graphic design of final report deliverables. Managed bookkeeping, including account reconciliation, financial reporting, and tax preparation, using Quickbooks. Authored a comprehensive training manual for the position.